<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>kirstiewhitaker on Whitaker Lab</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/authors/kirstiewhitaker/</link><description>Recent content in kirstiewhitaker on Whitaker Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://whitakerlab.github.io/authors/kirstiewhitaker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lab Meeting on 19 December 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-12-19-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-12-19-lab-meeting/</guid><description>This week I asked everyone in the lab to create a picture that visually illustrates (some part of) what they&amp;rsquo;ve done this year and a paragraph update. I&amp;rsquo;m so completely blown away by how wonderful they all are that I&amp;rsquo;m just going to jump right into them for this post.
There are a few celebrations and questions we&amp;rsquo;re thinking about at the end of the post too, so its a bumper edition!</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 17 October 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-10-17-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-10-17-lab-meeting/</guid><description>There are so many fantastic updates this week that were all in the hackmd notes because we spent the meeting hearing from Georgia about the Autistica/Turing Citizen Science project.
Check out the video below for a quick overview of why understanding autistic people&amp;rsquo;s sensory processing differences is important, and please join the project mailing list at https://tinyletter.com/AutisticaTuringCitizenScience to stay updated on our project.
Thank you to Kate Sytnik, a PhD student who studies sound guided navigation in gerbils in the Leibold lab at the University of Munich, who visited the lab this week.</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 10 October 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-10-10-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-10-10-lab-meeting/</guid><description>The week&amp;rsquo;s lab meeting fell on a Data Science for Mental Health Interest Group meeting and at the same time as a Turing Way development sprint, so the updates were asyncronous.
It was also World Mental Health Day so we collected together some recommendations to take care of yourself and your mental wellbeing.
If you didn&amp;rsquo;t receive the Turing Way newsletter you can read it (and sign up for it) at https://tinyletter.</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 3 October 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-10-03-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-10-03-lab-meeting/</guid><description>There was no lab meeting this week because there was a Turing Town Hall (where we get to grill the Institute Director).
We are delighted to share this video from May of the Pint of Science panel discussion featuring Kirstie Whitaker, Dianna Smith, Rebecca Sterry, Suzanne Iwai and Georgia Aitkenhead on Empowering autistic people through citizen science.
Now on to the updates!
Celebrations and cool things to share Kirstie is excited to be standing for membership of the inaugural Brain Imaging Data Structure (BIDS) Steering Group.</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 26 September 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-09-26-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-09-26-lab-meeting/</guid><description>We had a jam packed update this week (as usual! Do I write that every time? 🤔😆)
Scroll down past all the amazing updates to hear more about Ang and Yini&amp;rsquo;s work on a registered report to investigate the effects of polygenic risk for schizophrenia on brain structure.
Celebrations and cool things to share Kirstie is delighted to welcome Malvika Sharan to the lab as the community manager for The Turing Way.</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 19 September 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-09-19-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-09-19-lab-meeting/</guid><description>We didn&amp;rsquo;t have a lab meeting today because the timing of the meeting coincided with the Turing&amp;rsquo;s Data Science for Mental Health Interest Group.
The two talks were excellent. Neil Oxtoby presented an introduction to data-driven disease progression modelling, and Alexandra Young extended Neil&amp;rsquo;s presentation with a specific example of data-driven modelling and progression of subtypes of dementia.
This weekend - Saturday 21 September - is World Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Day and while we waited we watched Samuel L Jackson explain how you - and an orange 🍊 - can eliminate the stigma and dispel the myth that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing that can be done about dementia.</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 12 September 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-09-12-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-09-12-lab-meeting/</guid><description>We didn&amp;rsquo;t have lab meeting as Kirstie, Yini and Alex were at the Cambridge Neuroscience Symposium on Artificial and Biological Cognition, Sarah and Louise were at the research engineering team away day, Elizabeth was at Cognitive Computational Neuroscience in Berlin, and Malvika and Yo were on (what sounds like) fantastically relaxing holidays.
The group still had lots to share though!
Celebrations and cool things to share Sarah spent 4 days in Oslo with the Binder/JupyterHub team and had a wonderful time!</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 5 September 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-09-05-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-09-05-lab-meeting/</guid><description>We were in a tiny meeting room at the Alan Turing Institute today because the Institute was hosting a Data Study Group. Many apologies to Konrad Adler-Wagstyl and Hannah Spitzer who had lots of questions from the many lab members who connected through Zoom rather than over fill the room with CO2! Thank you so much for coming and presenting your work on the amazing MELD project (see below for more details.</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 29 August 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-08-29-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-08-29-lab-meeting/</guid><description>A few of the lab members were at the Cambridge Networks Day today, and so we cancelled lab meeting in real life.
There were still lots of great discussions and updates in the hackmd though. Keep reading to hear more!
Celebrations and cool things to share Kirstie is super proud of Google Summer of Code students Ruslan and Monica who have published their final reports! Congratulations, and thank you for all the great work ✨</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 22 August 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-08-22-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-08-22-lab-meeting/</guid><description>There were SO many great questions and conversations at this week&amp;rsquo;s lab meeting that we ran over time and ended up chatting for more than 2 hours.
There are lots of updates here, and some really fascinating questions that we didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to answer, but please do scroll to the end to see a few of Ruslan Yermakov&amp;rsquo;s excellent brain visualisations for the scona🍪 (Structural Covariance Network Analyses) project (https://github.com/WhitakerLab/scona).</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 15 August 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-08-15-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-08-15-lab-meeting/</guid><description>We had so many fascinating conversations this week that we didn&amp;rsquo;t get to spend as much time as we&amp;rsquo;d planned discussing how to make lab meetings effective and useful for all.
It seemed like interrupting team members sharing their expertise to talk about how to build a space where team members shared their expertise didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense at all 😉
Check out all the links below! We hope they&amp;rsquo;re useful to you ✨</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 01 August 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-08-01-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-08-01-lab-meeting/</guid><description>This week’s lab meet was petite but by no means picayune! We discussed ways to learn physics, Neurohackademy, and how to build trust and confidence in a group. Thanks Kirstie, Isla, and Sarah for your tips, suggestions, and a super interesting conversation!
Celebrations and cool things to share Kirstie is finding Neurohackademy great so far – with lots of awesome talks! Here are a select few 👇
Codeclimate for readable code: https://codeclimate.</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 25 July 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-07-25-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-07-25-lab-meeting/</guid><description>This week&amp;rsquo;s meeting was jaaaaaam packed!
Keep reading to learn about some of the fun things that folks are celebrating and thinking about and scroll to all the pictures at the end to see some fantastic updates from the lab projects.
Celebrations and cool things to share Kirstie kicked off the celebrations with a laundry list of items!
The existence of the first lab meeting blog post. The video of her keynote talk at PyData London from a couple of weeks ago (and the playlist for all the other talks).</description></item><item><title>Lab Meeting on 18 July 2019</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-07-18-lab-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2019-07-18-lab-meeting/</guid><description>This week we had a guest speaker - Bastian Greshake Tzvoras - but still managed to zoom through our celebrations and cool things to share.
We asked, but didn&amp;rsquo;t really answer, a few questions! Everyone (not just lab members) is welcome to brainstorm together in in our gitter room.
Celebrations and cool things to share Kirstie wrote a little blog post for Sky News about Alan Turing being on the £50 note.</description></item><item><title>WGS Founders Day speech</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-10-09-founders-day-speech/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-10-09-founders-day-speech/</guid><description>Yesterday I was back in Manchester for my school&amp;rsquo;s Founders Day. It&amp;rsquo;s a day where the whole senior school (11-18) and the oldest members of the junior school come together to celebrate everything that the girls in the school have achieved over the last year.
The choirs and orchestra were wonderful. This is during their performance of a medley of music from The Greatest Showman 😍 Writing the speech I attended Withington Girls' School from 1992 to 2001.</description></item><item><title>Citing works in progress</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-08-11-citing-wips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-08-11-citing-wips/</guid><description>I answered this question in person recently - at Neurohackademy - and I realised that it might be useful for others to read about. So in the spirit of &amp;ldquo;blog post or it didn&amp;rsquo;t happen&amp;rdquo; here are my thoughts on citing works in progress.
If you&amp;rsquo;re working under an open licence, anyone can use anything you&amp;rsquo;ve done I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of working open (check out this video of Mozilla Excecutive Director Mark Surman describing the concept if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of it before).</description></item><item><title>Diversity in data science and the legacy of Alan Turing</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-02-28-turing-life-and-legacy-talk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-02-28-turing-life-and-legacy-talk/</guid><description>Hi everyone! Here are my slides from my Lunch and Learn event today, hosted by the Macquarie Group Pride network. They represent my opinions and not (necessarily) those of the Turing or Macquarie Group (although I hope there&amp;rsquo;s at least some overlap here!)
I was asked to speak about the Life and legacy of Alan Turing and my talk has been heavily inspired by a fantastic panel discussion that I took part in last summer.</description></item><item><title>Open Science: Sharing is caring but is it privacy theft?</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-02-01-open-science-blog-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-02-01-open-science-blog-post/</guid><description>David Mehler and Kevin Weiner are members of the Communications Committee for the Organization for Human Brain Mapping. They reached out to six members of OHBM and asked them their opinions on open science. You can read our collated opinions at the PLOS blog.
(Spoiler alert, my answer to the post title, is it privacy theft? No. I don&amp;rsquo;t really address the ethical challenges of open science in this article. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to say about them, but maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll save those for another day.</description></item><item><title>Imitation Game at The Crick</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-01-17-imitation-game-at-the-crick/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-01-17-imitation-game-at-the-crick/</guid><description>Our next door neighbours here in Kings Cross - The Francis Crick Institute - have a wonderful series of events that are open to the public. Last Wednesday 10th January I was delighted to take part in a panel discussion after they showed The Imitation Game as part of the Science on Screen film festival.
The Imitation Game tells the story of Alan Turing who worked to break the German Enigma machine at Bletchley Park during World War II.</description></item><item><title>A very proud start to the new year</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-01-03-a-very-proud-start-to-the-new-year/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2018-01-03-a-very-proud-start-to-the-new-year/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been off the grid over new year in a beautiful hut in Northumbria. We did have phone signal (but no wifi), and I was reading twitter, but I was also trying to decompress and spend time with my partner so I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a huge amount of communicating online.
That meant I missed the opportunity on New Years Day to celebrate some of my friends being acknowledged as APS Rising Stars 🌟✨💫 and Prof Ian Goodyer made an OBE (Order of the British Empire) in the New Years Honours.</description></item><item><title>rOpenSci Fellowship Application 2017</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/resources/2017-09-01-ropensci-fellowship-application-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/resources/2017-09-01-ropensci-fellowship-application-2017/</guid><description>On this page you can find the answers submitted as my application to the rOpenSci fellowships program in 2017.
The application was submitted on September 1st at 10:48pm. (Over nine hours before the deadline 😉). It was required to fit on a maximum of 3 A4 pages. You can download the PDF here.
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License which means you can distribute, remix, tweak, and build upon these answers as long as you credit me for the original creation.</description></item><item><title>Interesting papers - August 2017</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-08-07-interesting-papers-august2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-08-07-interesting-papers-august2017/</guid><description>In the Bullmore lab meetings recently I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned a few papers that I&amp;rsquo;d seen on twitter and I promised to email them around.Here is that email (but as a blog post for posterity!)
Please note that these are absolutely not the only papers I&amp;rsquo;ve thought were interesting, just a non-random selection that I think others may want to know about ☺️
Genetic analyses of depression Two papers caught my eye. One from the Psychiatric Genomics Consortium and one from Andrew McIntosh and colleagues using UK Biobank data.</description></item><item><title>Talk at SOBP 2017</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-05-19-sobp-annual-meeting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-05-19-sobp-annual-meeting/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to present our work on structural brain development during adolescence at the Society of Biological Psychiatry 2017 annual meeting in San Diego.
My talk is part of a symposium on Network Architectures of the Healthy Brain as Constraints for the Spatiotemporal Patterning of Disease. We were brought together by chairs Armin Raznahan and Mallar Chakravarty and it should be a really fascinating afternoon session.
My slides are linked below, and you can read the paper I&amp;rsquo;m presenting at PNAS.</description></item><item><title>OpenCon application 2016</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/resources/2017-05-13-opencon-application-2016/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/resources/2017-05-13-opencon-application-2016/</guid><description>OpenCon is a conference for early career academics and seeks to empower the next generation to advance Open Access, Open Education, and Open Data.
These are the essays from my (successful) application to attend OpenCon 2016 in Washington DC.
The application was submitted on Monday 11th July 2016.
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License which means you can distribute, remix, tweak, and build upon these answers as long as you credit me for the original creation.</description></item><item><title>How I became a Mozilla Fellow for Science</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-05-08-mozilla-fellowship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-05-08-mozilla-fellowship/</guid><description>My Mozilla Fellowship journey I wrote a blog post for the Mozilla Science Lab to encourage everyone to apply for the 2017 Mozilla fellows for science cohort.
You can check out the whole post at the Mozilla Science Lab blog but here are a couple of key links.
I&amp;rsquo;ve put my applications online in the resources section of this website if you want to see what I wrote:
My unsuccessful 2015 application My successful 2016 application Here&amp;rsquo;s where you can find out more information and apply!</description></item><item><title>What's Wrong With Science?</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-05-05-whats-wrong-with-science/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-05-05-whats-wrong-with-science/</guid><description>I was invited to discuss the &amp;ldquo;reproducibility crisis&amp;rdquo; for BBC Newshour Extra on the World Service.
The other panel members were Brian Nosek, Jeff Leek, Daniël Lakens and Chris Graf. Give them all a follow on twitter, they&amp;rsquo;re awesome people!
The one hour discussion is available at the BBC Newshour Extra site and you can download the podcast from there to listen offline.
Let me know what you think!</description></item><item><title>London MicroWOW</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-05-03-london-microwow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-05-03-london-microwow/</guid><description>Learning to work openly using git and GitHub On Friday 28th April the wonderful Bruno Vieira, my fellow Mozilla Fellow for Science was in London and we decided to run a micro Working Open Workshop (#microWOW!)
This is in contrast to a full WOW which is a two day extravaganza and a mini WOW which is a one day event. We only had one evening but we tried to fit as much of what we knew about working open and collaborating using git and GitHub as possible.</description></item><item><title>Mozilla Fellows for Science Application 2015</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/resources/2017-04-28-mozilla-science-fellowship-application-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/resources/2017-04-28-mozilla-science-fellowship-application-2015/</guid><description>On this page you can find the answers from my (unsuccessful) application to become a Mozilla Fellow for Science in 2015.
The application was submitted on August 14th at 7:01pm while on holiday in Edinburgh! I had some delicious cocktails that evening 😊 🍸.
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License which means you can distribute, remix, tweak, and build upon these answers as long as you credit me for the original creation.</description></item><item><title>Mozilla Fellows for Science Application 2016</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/resources/2017-04-28-mozilla-science-fellowship-application-2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/resources/2017-04-28-mozilla-science-fellowship-application-2016/</guid><description>On this page you can find the answers from my (successful!) application to become a Mozilla Fellow for Science in 2016.
The application was submitted on Jul 15th at 11:33pm (swoosh, just before the deadline).
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License which means you can distribute, remix, tweak, and build upon these answers as long as you credit me for the original creation.</description></item></channel></rss>