<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>moz-open-leaders on Whitaker Lab</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/tags/moz-open-leaders/</link><description>Recent content in moz-open-leaders on Whitaker Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://whitakerlab.github.io/tags/moz-open-leaders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My experiences as a Mozilla Open Leader</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-12-14-mozilla-open-leadership/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-12-14-mozilla-open-leadership/</guid><description>Mozilla Open Leadership Earlier this year Mozilla Science Lab awarded a mini grant to me to refactor the Whitaker Lab&amp;rsquo;s openly developed project Brain Networks in Python. I also applied successfully to the recently concluded 4th Mozilla Open Leadership Training cohort. With the application deadline for the next round of both approaching I thought I should share my experiences.
I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure when I sent my application in what open leadership training meant.</description></item><item><title>Boaty-McBrainNetworksInPython</title><link>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-09-27-boaty-mcbrainnetworksinpython/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://whitakerlab.github.io/blog/2017-09-27-boaty-mcbrainnetworksinpython/</guid><description>Help us choose a new name for our brain networks software package Source: University of California via Giphy.
The Whitaker Lab has been working on some code currently known as BrainNetworksInPython with the intention to release it as a python package.
BrainNetworksInPython is an openly developed toolkit for conducting analysis on structural covariance networks in the brain. To learn more you can check out our GitHub repository. We&amp;rsquo;d like to conform to the Python package naming conventions given by PEP 8 &amp;ndash; Style Guide for Python Code:</description></item></channel></rss>